Welcome back to the webcast where we spotlight some of the coolest people and projects in the ecosystem and today we're joined by Ben, CMO of Raydium.
欢迎回到我们的网络访谈，在这里我们聚焦生态系统中最酷的人物和项目，今天我们请到了Raydium的首席营销官Ben。
I remember going to my first Breakpoint in 2022 and the FTX collapse was happening and I looked around the room and I said, these guys are never leaving Solana.
我记得2022年参加我的第一次Breakpoint大会，当时FTX正在崩溃，我环顾四周说，这些人永远不会离开Solana。
Three years ago BlackRock was like, no, no, we hate crypto.
三年前贝莱德还在说，不不，我们讨厌加密货币。
It's funny how quickly the world changed.
世界变化如此之快，真有趣。
So we went through this evolution of being this infrastructure provider in the background to being a full stack liquidity provider and full stack trading tool.
我们经历了一个演变过程，从幕后的基础设施提供商，到全栈流动性提供商和全栈交易工具。
And a big part of that obviously was expansion to perpetuals, which is where the partnership with Orderly came in.
其中很重要的一部分显然是扩展到永续合约，这就是我们与Orderly合作的切入点。
I think perps will always be interesting.
我认为永续合约永远都会很有趣。
I think generally people care less about owning the asset and they want to care about having exposure to the asset.
我认为总体上人们不太在乎拥有资产本身，他们更在乎对资产的敞口。
I've been in this industry for five years and these are the rooms that us crypto people were shunned in and now suddenly we got the suits in the room.
我在这个行业待了五年，这些曾经将我们加密人拒之门外的房间，现在突然来了很多穿西装的人。
I think we are still in this speculative era of crypto where primarily people look at it as a way to make money and just better financial management.
我认为我们仍然处于加密货币的投机时代，人们主要将其视为赚钱和更好地进行财务管理的方式。
But I think we're starting to inch towards more of the utility phase of crypto.
但我认为我们正开始逐步迈向加密货币的实用阶段。